所有的显示屏都将直播婚礼仪式，长官
The ceremony will be carried on all viewing screens, sir.
很好
Good.
舰桥正呼叫你
There's a call for you from the bridge.
- 我是寇克 - 地球前哨2号
- Kirk here. - Still no answer
还是没有回应，舰长
from Earth Outpost Number 2, captain.
现在连3号也没动静了
And now Number 3 has gone silent.
保持去4号的航线，随时汇报
Maintain course to Outpost 4. Keep me informed.
通话结束
Kirk out.
从有第一艘木质船起
Since the days of the first wooden vessels,
所有的船长都享有一项愉快的特权
all shipmasters have had one happy privilege.
那就是给新人主婚
That of uniting two people in the bonds of matrimony.
我们今天欢聚一堂，同你，安吉拉·马丁
And so we are gathered here today with you, Angela Martine,
以及你，罗伯特·汤姆林森，在船员们的见证下
and you, Robert Tomlinson, in the sight of your fellows,
基于我们的法律以及信仰
in accordance with our laws and our many beliefs,
- 现在你们可以宣誓… - 警报！警报！所有人员注意，警报！
- so that you may pledge your-- - Alert! Alert! All decks, alert!
警报！警报！舰长请到舰桥！
Alert! Alert! Captain to the bridge!
- 所有人员，警报！ - 我是寇克
- All decks, alert! - Kirk here.
地球前哨站4号报告说他们正受到攻击
Earth Outpost 4 reports they're under attack.
攻击来源于一艘不明身份的飞船
A space vessel, identity unknown.
全速前进，所有人员，红色警报
Full ahead. All decks, Condition Red.
所有人员，红色警报
All decks, Condition Red.
宇宙，最后的边疆
Space, the final frontier.
这是进取号星舰的航程
These are the voyages Of the starship Enterprise.
它的五年任务，是去探索未知的新世界
Its five-year mission: To explore strange new worlds,
找寻新的生命与新的文明
to seek out new life and new civilizations,
勇敢地航向前人未至之境
to boldly go where no man has gone before.
【星际迷航：原初】
荣誉出品
本字幕仅供学习交流，严禁用于商业途径
-=TLF字幕组=-
翻译：刘诗濛 马田的心事
校对：心痕依
第一季第14集
恐怖平衡
舰长日志，星历1709.2
Captain's log, stardate 1709.2.
我们正在巡查守卫于罗慕鲁斯、瑞摩斯
Patrolling outposts guarding the Neutral Zone
和别的星系之间中立区的前哨站
between planets Romulus and Remus and the rest of the galaxy,
收到了来自4号前哨站的紧急来电
received emergency call from Outpost 4.
联邦星舰进取号正前往调查并救援中
The USS Enterprise is moving to investigate and assist.
4号前哨站报告说正收到攻击，长官
Outpost 4 reported under attack, sir.
然后信息中断了
Then message terminates.
确认无误，舰长
Verified, captain.
我们正全速前进，长官
Our speed is now maximum, sir.
位置，现在速度下距离4号前哨站8分钟，长官
Position, eight minutes from Outpost 4 at this velocity, sir.
- 史考特… - 我已经跟发动机组人员谈过了
- Scotty... - I've already talked
长官，我们会努力让飞船再快些
to my engine room, sir. We'll get more speed out of her.
4号前哨站有提到关于攻击飞船的信息吗，上尉？
Did Outpost 4 give anything at all on the attacking vessel, lieutenant?
无法确认目标，长官
No identification, sir.
不难猜出谁在进攻，长官
There can't be much doubt who's attacking, sir.
史波克先生…
Mr. Spock...
把这块区域的星图放到屏幕上
...put this star sector on our screen.
现在显示我们的位置
Now show our position.
把这个发送给所有甲板，上尉
Signal this to all decks, lieutenant.
所有甲板待命，长官
All decks standing by, sir.
这里是舰长
This is the captain speaking.
接下来的行动中，所有人不得有任何失误
In our next action, we can risk neither miscalculation nor error
或者差错
by any man aboard.
仔细听，科学官
Listen carefully. Science officer.
在你们屏幕的地图上，你会注意到
Referring to the map on your screens, you will note,
在我们的飞船前方
beyond the moving position of our vessel,
有一条地球前哨站组成的防线
a line of Earth outpost stations.
前哨站都建在小行星上，用于监视中立区
Constructed on asteroids, they monitor the Neutral Zone,
中立区是在一个多世纪前地球与罗慕鲁斯的战后
established by treaty after the Earth-Romulan Conflict
由双方协商建立
of over a century ago.
你们可能还记得这段历史
As you may recall from your histories,
这次战争，按我们今天的标准
this conflict was fought, by our standards today,
使用了原始的原子武器和航天飞船
with primitive atomic weapons and in primitive space vessels,
使得双方都无法手下留情，也无法抓获战俘
which allowed no quarter, no captives.
甚至不存在飞船间的可视通话
Nor was there even ship-to-ship visual communication.
因此，目前人类和罗慕兰人双方都未见过彼此
Therefore, no human, Romulan or ally has ever seen the other.
地球人觉得罗慕兰人好战，残忍而反复无常
Earth believes the Romulans to be warlike, cruel, treacherous.
罗慕兰人怎么看地球人就只有他们自己知道了
And only the Romulans know what they think of Earth.
战后合约，通过子空间无线电制定
The treaty, set by subspace radio,
成立了这片中立区
established this Neutral Zone,
进入中立区，不管哪方
entry into which, by either side,
都会被认为是宣战的行为
would constitute an act of war.
目前为止还没人打破这个合约
The treaty has been unbroken since that time.
舰长
Captain.
有一件事你们必须清楚
What you do not know and must now be told
我在这件事情上的所有命令都必须准确执行
is that my command orders on this subject are precise and inviolable.
任何行为，任何挑衅…
No act, no provocation...
都不能被当成违反合约进入中立区的理由
...will be considered sufficient reason to violate the zone.
我们可以自卫
We may defend ourselves,
但是，如有必要
but, if necessary,
为避免星际大战
to avoid interspace war,
这些前哨站和这艘飞船都是可以牺牲的
both these outposts and this vessel will be considered expendable.
舰长，完毕
Captain out.
我们知道4号前哨站被攻击了，长官
We know Outpost 4 has been attacked, sir,
所以如果我们现在拦截罗慕兰飞船
so if we intercept Romulans now--
一个世纪了，罗慕兰飞船长什么样子，斯泰尔斯先生？
After a whole century, what will a Romulan ship look like, Mr. Stiles?
他们恐怕不会无线电告诉我们他们的身份吧
I doubt if they'll radio and identify themselves.
你看见就知道，长官，他们的飞船被漆成猛禽的样子
You'll know, sir. They're painted like a giant bird of prey.
我还不知道历史也是你的专长
I had no idea that history was your speciality.
家族历史
Family history.
我们家族那时有一个人是舰长
There was a Captain Stiles in the space service then.
两个中校，不少基层军官
Two commanders, several junior officers.
全部牺牲了，长官
All lost in that war, sir.
他们的战争，斯泰尔斯先生
Their war, Mr. Stiles.
不是你的
Not yours.
不要忘了这一点
Don't forget it.
是，长官
Yes, sir.
2号前哨站进入探测范围，舰长
Outpost 2 coming into sensor range, captain.
2号前哨站是最先失去联系的吗，上尉？
Outpost 2 was the first to go silent, lieutenant?
是的，舰长，然后是3号，相隔一个小时
Yes, captain. Then Outpost 3 an hour later.
扫描2号前哨站的区域
Sweeping the area of Outpost 2.
感应区显示，无法确定
Sensor reading, indefinite.
再次扫描3号前哨站
Double-checking Outpost 3.
显示尘埃和废墟
I read dust and debris.
2个前哨站都没了
Both Earth outposts gone.
他们所在的小行星…
And the asteroids they were constructed on...
被摧毁了
...pulverized.
跟最近的指挥基地取得联系
Open a channel to our nearest command base.
每15分钟汇报我们的位置和状态
Quarter-hour reports on our position and status.
是，长官
Yes, sir.
让所有人进入战斗岗位，苏鲁先生
Call battle stations, Mr. Sulu.
战斗岗位，所有人进入战斗岗位
Battle stations. All hands to battle stations.
战斗岗位，所有甲板请确认
Battle stations. Battle stations. All decks acknowledge.
所有甲板已确认，长官，所有甲板就位
All decks acknowledge, sir. All stations show green.
启动主相位炮，斯泰尔斯先生
Energize main phasers, Mr. Stiles.
所有武器最大功率
All weapons to full power.
相位炮控制室
Phaser Control Room,
启动，请确认
energize. Acknowledge.
相位炮控制室确定，所有武器功率最大
Phaser Control acknowledging. All weapons energizing to full.
结婚日快乐，差一点
Happy wedding day. Almost.
你不会这么轻易逃过去的
You won't get off my hook this easily.
我会嫁给你的，先生
I'm going to marry you, mister,
不管有没有战争和相位武器
battle or phaser weapons notwithstanding.
嗯，同时，至少暂时
Well, meanwhile, temporarily, at least,
我还是你的上司
I'm still your superior officer.
要适应啊，“先生”
So get with it, mister.
- 左舷武器就位 - 右舷武器和中央武器
- Port weapons show ready. - Starboard and midship weapons
- 就位 - 收到
- show ready. - Acknowledge.
所有武器电能就绪
All weapons batteries ready.
4号前哨站，5分钟就到，长官
Outpost 4, now five minutes away, sir.
在感应器看来，舰长，至少4号站还在
And showing on my sensors, captain. At least it's still there.
长官，与4号重新取得联系，转为公放模式
Sir, regaining contact with Outpost 4. Switching to speakers.
4号前哨站，能收到吗，进取号？
Outpost 4. Do you read me, Enterprise?
这是中校汉森
This is Commander Hansen.
我是寇克，我们马上就到，汉森，情况如何？
Kirk here. We're minutes away, Hansen. What's your status?
2、3、8号前哨站都没了
Outposts 2, 3 and 8 are gone.
被未知武器完全摧毁
Unknown weapon. Completely destroyed,
虽然我们预先收到警报
even though we were alerted.
把偏转器防护罩开到了最大
Had our deflector shield on maximum.
但被极大的能量攻击了
Hit by enormous power.
第一次攻击炸飞了偏转器防护罩
First attack blew our deflector shield.
如果他们在我们没有防护罩时再次攻击…
If they hit us again with our deflector shield gone...
你听到了吗，进取号？
Do you read me, Enterprise?
确认是什么攻击你的，汉森
Confirm what hit you, Hansen.
什么样的飞船？身份
What vessel? Identity.
太空飞船…只看见了一眼…
Space vessel... Only glimpse of...
- 你能为我们确认入侵者的位置吗？ - 不能
- Can you locate the intruder for us? - Negative.
它好像消失了
It seems to have disappeared somehow.
我能在屏幕上看见你了，转到视频通话
I have you on my screen now. Switching to visual.
接通过去
Tie us in.
接通了，长官
Tied in, sir.
进取号，你能看见吗？
Enterprise, can you see it?
我的控制台
My command post here.
我们在小行星上一英里深的地下
We're a mile deep, on an asteroid,
钢筋结构，并且还有防护罩，结果成这样
almost solid iron, and even through our deflectors, it did this.
- 你能看见吗？ - 能，能看见，汉森
- Can you see? - Affirmative. You're visual, Hansen.
- 关于入侵者你有什么信息吗？ - 无法确认身份
- What do you have on the intruder? - No identification.
没有回应我们的警告，只看见它一眼…
No answer to our challenge. Only a glimpse of...
然后它朝我们发射了什么，像是高能量等离子体
Then it fired something at us. Some form of high-energy plasma.
难以置信的能量，然后整个飞船就消失了
Fantastic power. And then the whole vessel disappeared.
但是它还在附近，我们的感应器就只发现这些
But it's out there somewhere. Our sensors show that much.
进取号，我们的观测屏显示有东西过来了
Enterprise, something coming on our viewing screen.
- 朝我们飞速前进 - 把我们锁定在你的显示屏上
- Coming at us fast. - Lock us on to your screen.
切换中
Switching.
你能看见吗，进取号？你能看见吗？
Can you see it, Enterprise? Can you see it?
在显示屏中央，它渐渐显形了
It's becoming visible in the centre of my screen.
你还能发射相位炮吗？我们还在射程外
Do you have phaser capacity? We're still out of range.
不行，相位炮没了，武器人员都牺牲了
Negative. Phasers, gone. Weapons crew, dead.
发警告，警告那飞船离开
Make challenge. Warn that ship off.
我在努力，长官，他们不回应
I'm trying to, sir. They don't acknowledge.
4号前哨站…
Outpost 4...
成碎片了，舰长
...disintegrated, captain.
- 找到入侵者，史波克先生 - 消失了
- Position of the intruder, Mr. Spock. - Disappeared.
很奇怪他们为什么会显形那么一会
Interesting how they became visible for just a moment.
当他们开火时
When they opened fire.
也许必须那样才能使用他们的武器
Perhaps necessary when they use their weapons.
感应器上发现了一个信号点，舰长
I have a blip on the motion sensor, captain.
- 可能是入侵者 - 最大化
- Could be the intruder. - Go to full magnification.
放大到最大了，长官
Screen is on full mag, sir.
我没看见任何东西
I don't see anything.
我没明白
I can't understand it.
隐形在理论上是可能的，舰长
Invisibility is theoretically possible, captain.
选择性的扭曲光线，但是需要极大的能量
The selective bending of light. But the power cost is enormous.
他们也许解决了能量的问题
They may have solved that problem.
正继续发警告，长官，还是没有回应
Continuing to challenge, sir. Still no response.
停止
Discontinue.
联系剩余的前哨站，让他们报告各自区域
Contact remaining outposts, have them signal us
观测或者感应到的东西
any sightings or sensor readings in their area.
那个信号点改变航线了，舰长
Blip has changed its heading, captain.
看起来很漫不经心的样子
And in a very leisurely manoeuvre.
他们好像还不知道我们
They may not be aware of us.
他们的隐形屏可能是双向的
Their invisibility screen may work both ways.
那么大的能量消耗…
With that kind of power consumption...
他们可能就无法看见我们
...they may not be able to see us.
他的前进方向现在是111
His heading is now 111,
标示14
mark 14.
恰恰是罗慕兰飞船会选的路，吉姆
The exact heading a Romulan vessel would take, Jim,
去往中立区…然后回家
toward the Neutral Zone...and home.
平行飞行航线
Parallel course.
不应该是拦截航线吗，长官？
Don't you mean interception course, sir?
不是，你和苏鲁先生要让飞船的速度和航线
Negative. You and Mr. Sulu will match course and speed
跟我们感应到的物体一样，完全一样
with the object on our sensors, exactly move for move.
如果它也有感应器
If he has sensors,
我要他认为我们只是他们的反射体，镜像
I want him to think that we're a reflection, an echo.
除非我亲自下令
Under no circumstances are you to cross
否则禁止踏入中立区一步
into the Neutral Zone without my direct orders.
- 明白，长官 - 取消紧急集结点
- Acknowledged, sir. - Cancel battle stations.
- 全体舰员，紧急待命 - 长官，紧急集结点已取消
- All decks, standby alert. - Cancel battle stations, sir.
舰长
Captain
出于敬意，请允许我提醒您刚才发生了什么
may I respectfully remind the captain what has happened.
罗慕兰人已越过中立区
The Romulans have crossed the Neutral Zone,
攻击了我们的前哨基地，杀害了我们的同胞
attacked our outposts, killed our men.
- 斯泰尔斯 - 考虑到以上事实
- Mr. Stiles-- - Add to that the fact
- 这种行为是偷袭 - 斯泰尔斯
- that it was a sneak attack. - Mr. Stiles,
- 你在质疑我的命令吗？ - 没有，长官
- are you questioning my orders? - Negative, sir.
我是说舰船上可能潜伏着敌方间谍
I'm pointing out that we could have Romulan spies aboard this ship.
长官，我同意他的看法
I agree, sir.
我建议对全舰保持安全警告
Respectfully recommend all decks maintain security alert.
就这么办，对全舰发出安全警告
Very well. All decks, security alert.
长官，安全警告已发
Security alert, sir.
长官，接收到通讯信号
Picking up communication, sir.
- 来自罗慕兰人的舰船 - 传进来
- It's from their ship. - Pipe it in.
长官，听起来像是密码
Sounds like code, sir.
舰长，我能搞定
I have a fix on it, captain.
我想我能给它定位，并取得对方舰桥的照片
I believe I can lock on it, get a picture of their bridge.
传到屏幕上来
Put it on the screen.
密码解得怎么样了？
Decoding?
- 长官，破译员正在破译 - 给史波克不就结了
- Cryptography is working on it, sir. - Give it to Spock.
斯泰尔斯，刚才那话我没听清
I didn't quite get that, Mr. Stiles.
- 长官，没别的意思 - 再说一遍
- Nothing, sir. - Repeat it.
长官，我是说史波克也许能翻译这些信号
I was suggesting that Mr. Spock could probably translate it for you, sir.
那我就认为你是在称赞他出色的破译能力
I assume you're complimenting Mr. Spock on his ability to decode.
长官，我不确定这是我的想法
I'm not sure, sir.
这位先生，至少你能确定一件事
Well, here's one thing you can be sure of, mister.
把偏见之心留在舱房里
Leave any bigotry in your quarters.
舰桥上可没它的一席之地
There's no room for it on the bridge.
我的意思够明白了吗？
Do I make myself clear?
长官，明白
You do, sir.
传送已终止
Transmission has been cut off.
长官，我把它录下了
I made a tape of it, sir.
干得好
Very well.
舰长，前方有物体出现
Something visual ahead, captain.
体型巨大
At extreme range.
长官，对方正在改变航道
He's changing course, sir.
- 舵手，跟着它 - 长官，正在转弯
- Stay with him, helm. - Turning, sir.
我们慢慢现形了，开启隐形系统
We grow visible. Attend the cloaking system.
中校，此举耗能过多，在无敌军…
It consumes much power, commander. With no enemy to--
那个地球前哨呼叫了
That Earth outpost called
一艘地球舰船 现在正跟着我们
to an Earth vessel. Now it follows us.
不退也不近
Which neither retreats nor grows nearer.
我们转向，他们也转
Which turns as we turn.
中校，我认为跟在后面的是我们的追随者
Commander, it is our judgement we run from a reflection.
也许是，但我说了算
Perhaps so, but my judgement prevails.
长官，隐形系统已开启
Cloaking system on, sir.
靠近中立区真好
It is good we approach the Neutral Zone.
不久就能看见家乡的繁星了
Not too soon for me to see the stars of home.
我知道他们跟着我们
I know they are following.
倘若对方真是一艘地球舰船
But if an Earth ship
那为何不攻击我们呢？
why does he not attack?
首先，研究对手，找其弱势
First, study the enemy, seek weakness.
若我是敌方指挥官，我定会这么做
If I were their commander, that is what I would do.
长官找德西乌斯有何事
My commander sent for Decius.
你发了条消息
A message was dispatched.
- 此举违反了禁言之规 - 中校，消息加过密了
- You've broken the rule of silence. - Only in code, commander.
为的是将这次光荣的使命告知执政官
To inform our Praetor of this glorious mission.
而你的大意可能会让使命胎死腹中
Your carelessness might have ended this glorious mission.
军衔降两级，归位
You are reduced two steps in rank. Return to post.
中校，小心行事
Take care, commander.
他人脉颇广
He has friends.
他的朋友意味着权势，权势等同危险
And friends of his kind mean power, and power is danger.
危险是我的老伙计
Danger and I are old companions.
你我并肩作战百次
We've seen a hundred campaigns together,
可我还是不懂你
and still I do not understand you.
你懂
I think you do.
我不需要告诉你，当我们带着能证明
No need to tell you what happens the moment we reach home
地球人缺陷的证据回家时会发生什么
with proof of the earthmen's weakness.
我们会找到证据
And we will have proof.
那艘地球舰船定会尾随我们
The Earth commander will follow, he must,
他一旦发起进攻，我们立即将其摧毁
and when he attacks, we will destroy him.
这场战争就是我们的归家之礼
Our gift to the homeland, another war.
倘若我们是强壮的一方
If we are the strong,
我们难道不该主动挑起战争吗？
is this not the signal for war?
非得一直如此吗？
Must it always be so?
一路上我们痛失多少同伴了？
How many comrades have we lost in this way?
中校，我们的命运……
Our portion, commander...
- 就是服从 - 服从
- ...is obedience. - Obedience!
责任
Duty.
除了战死还是战死
Death and more death.
很快就能满足执行官的要求了
Soon even enough for the Praetor's taste.
百夫长…
Centurion...
我希望回家之前我们能被人毁灭了
...I find myself wishing for destruction before we can return.
别担心
Worry not.
我和你一样训练有素，职责所在，定当遵守
Like you, I am too well-trained in my duty to permit it.
继续防御撤退
Continue evasive manoeuvres.
现在回到最初的航线
Now, back to the first course.
长官，他们在转向，我们紧跟其后
They're turning, sir. We're staying with them.
朝方位111，标记14均速行驶
Steady on 111, mark 14.
舰长，他们回到初始航线了
Back on their original course, captain.
驶往中立区
Toward the Neutral Zone.
导航员，我们现在身在何处？
What's our position, navigator?
长官，不掉头的话
We'll enter the Neutral Zone in less than an hour, sir.
不到一小时就能到中立区了
Assuming, of course, that we don't turn back.
舰长，4号前哨的残骸已带到舰上
We now have aboard debris from Outpost 4, captain.
带到简报室，准备好了吗，同志们？
Bring it to the Briefing Room. Are you ready, gentlemen?
这是前哨保护罩的一部分
From the outpost's protective shield.
由洛德尼合金锻造而成
[rodinium为一种虚构的物质]
Cast rodinium.
这是目前科学领域里已知最硬的物质
This is the hardest substance known to our science.
实验室认为是包裹着能量的等离子
The lab theorizes an enveloping energy plasma,
导致了内爆的发生
forcing an implosion.
有什么看法吗？
Comments?
显然对方的武器比我们先进
Obviously their weaponry is superior to ours,
而且他们有一个实用的隐形屏
and they have a practical invisibility screen.
你说的是策略
You're discussing tactics.
你知道这到底意味着什么吗？
Do you realise what this really comes down to?
对方的下一步行动决定了数百万人的生命
Millions and millions of lives hanging on what this vessel does next.
医生，如果对方行动失败，劫难便可以避免
Or on what this vessel fails to do, doctor.
对，不错，但是同志们，问题仍未解决
Yes, well, gentlemen, the question still remains, can we engage them
如果开战，我们的胜算大吗？
with a reasonable possibility of victory?
没问题，对方使用的是简易脉冲能
No question. Their power is simple impulse.
- 也就是说我们可以赶超他们 - 长官，可以追击
- Meaning we can outrun them. - To be used in chasing them
也可以逃跑
or retreating, sir.
斯泰尔斯，接着说，开会就是为了集思广益
Go ahead, Mr. Stiles. I called this session for opinions.
- 我们得立即发起进攻 - 说说理由
- We have to attack immediately. - Explain.
他们此刻仍处于我方地盘
They're still on our side of the Neutral Zone.
毫无疑问对方违反了条约
There would be no doubt that they broke the treaty.
进攻吗？看不见目标怎么进攻？
Attack? Without a visible target?
- 该怎样定位相位炮？ - 可以利用传感器
- How do we aim our phasers? - Aim with sensors.
精度虽然不高，但如果我们地毯式地…
Not accurate, but if we blanket them--
寄希望于在对方没瞄准我们之前找到他们吗？
And hope for a lucky shot before they zero in on us?
如果我们不发起进攻
And if we don't?
对方会说我们看见他们的武器后吓跑了
Once back, they'll report that we saw their weapons and ran.
他们也可以说把我们毁了啊
And if they could report that they destroyed us?
他们是罗慕兰人
These are Romulans!
从他们眼前逃走意味着主动挑起战争
You run away from them and you guarantee war!
他们会倾尽所有来报复我们
They'll be back, not just one ship, but with everything they've got.
科学官，你明白，你对这些人知根知底
You know that, Mr. Science Officer. You're the expert on these people.
但对此你只字不提，为什么？
But you've always left out that one point. Why?
我很想知道原因
I'm very interested in why.
斯泰尔斯，坐下
Sit down, mister.
我同意发起进攻
I agree. Attack.
你的建议是以战止战吗？
Are you suggesting we fight to prevent a fight?
依据呢？
Based on what?
基于100多年前的那场战争的记忆吗？
Memories of a war over a century ago?
对一族素未谋面的外星人的理论认识吗？
On theories about a people we've never even met face to face?
我们知道他们的长相
We know what they look like.
斯泰尔斯，我们的确知道
Yes, indeed we do, Mr. Stiles.
如果罗慕兰人是瓦肯人的分支
And if the Romulans are an offshoot
而我认为这极有可能
of my Vulcan blood-- And I think this likely.
那么主动进攻便更为必要了
--then attack becomes even more imperative.
史波克，战争从来都不是必要之事
War is never imperative, Mr. Spock.
医生，对方认为是
It is for them, doctor.
与地球一样，瓦肯也曾经历过战争殖民时代
Vulcan, like Earth, had its aggressive, colonizing period.
与地球相比，手段更为野蛮
Savage, even by Earth standards.
如果罗慕兰人仍崇尚武力
And if the Romulans retained this martial philosophy,
那我们便不能显露弱点
then weakness is something we dare not show.
你想昧着良心发动一场星际大战吗？
Do you want a galactic war on your conscience?
- 舰长呼叫舰桥 - 舰长，我是乌乎拉
- Captain to bridge. - This is Uhura, captain.
- 我们身在何处？ - 长官，沿原航线行驶
- What's our position? - Course unchanged, sir.
预计将于21分钟后到达警戒线
Estimating treaty boundary in 21 minutes.
你还在广播战术报告吗？
Are you continuing to broadcast tactical reports?
- 是的，长官 - 此处情况如何？
- Affirmative, captain. - And at this distance?
3小时左右后将收到第一条信息的回馈
Approximately three hours before receiving a reply to our first message.
谢谢你，上尉
Thank you, lieutenant.
史波克，检查前方航线
Check our course ahead, Mr. Spock.
正前方有一颗7等彗星
A comet, magnitude 7, dead ahead.
敌方正改变航向向它驶去
And the intruder changing course toward it.
- 伊卡洛斯4号彗星，结构如何？ - 相当普通
- Comet Icarus 4. Composition? - Quite ordinary.
一个电离团，一条冷冻气化微粒的尾巴
An ionized mass, a trail of frozen vapour particles.
物体从它身边驶过时，隐形装置也会…
And when an object passes through it, even an invisible object--
留下一条可见的拖痕
It leaves a visible trail.
同志们，机会来了
Our chance, gentlemen.
做好进攻准备，所有人员进入战斗岗位
Prepare to attack. All hands battle stations.
老骨头，希望这次没你什么事儿
I hope we won't need your services, Bones.
但愿如此，吉姆，这盘你赌大了
Amen to that. You're taking a big gamble, Jim.
备战情况
Battle status.
舰长，所有站点均已配备人手
All stations manned, captain.
激光武器已能量化，邻近爆破准备完毕
Phaser weapons energized, set for proximity blast.
敌方正朝彗尾行进
Intruder now bearing directly for comet's tail.
斯泰尔斯，精确地标出敌方入口坐标
Plot his exact point of entry, Mr. Stiles.
长官，坐标已算出，准备标记
Computed. On the board, sir.
一旦对方开始进入彗尾，舰船就会慢慢现形
The moment he begins entering the comet's tail, he becomes visible.
同志们，停止追随
End run, gentlemen.
我们去另一头，时刻一到，撒网捕鱼
We'll swing around the other side and catch him at that moment.
遵命，舰长
Acknowledged, captain.
舰长，敌方未改变行驶方向
He's maintaining that bearing, captain.
苏鲁，拿下它
Let's get him, Mr. Sulu.
这真是视觉享受
How pleasing to the eye it is.
看，夜之奇迹
Behold, a marvel in the darkness.
玩手段你有一套
You spoke of entrapment.
百夫长，彗尾中的部分粒子会干扰他们的探测装置
Its many particles will obscure their sensing device, Centurion.
中校，我们进去了
We enter it, commander.
一旦彻底屏蔽，我们就攻他个措手不及
Once fully obscured, we will turn suddenly back upon our adversary.
中校，对方舰船从屏幕上消失了
At last, the screen is clear, commander.
- 消失？ - 敌方不再尾随我们了
- Clear? - Our reflection no longer follows us.
结束一号演习，快
Escape manoeuvre one! Quickly!
- 舰长，传感通信正在消失 - 稳步跟上
- We're losing sensor contact, captain. - Steady as she goes.
相位炮手准备好了吗？
Phaser crews ready?
长官，相位炮手现已待命
Phaser crew signal ready, sir.
敌方舰船的现形期很短
He'll only be visible for a moment.
随时待命
Stand by.
长官，什么都…
Sir, nothing in--
- 最后一刻，敌方必… - 必会预料到我们的计划
- At the last moment, he must-- - Must have guessed our move.
- 舵手，右满舵 - 右满舵
- Hard to starboard, helm! - Hard to starboard.
他做了本该我做的事
He did exactly what I would've done.
我不会再小瞧他了
I won't underestimate him again.
现在隐秘射击，采用其他发射方式
Now, fire blind. Lay down a pattern.
Z字形射击，所有相位炮发射
Traverse pattern. All phasers fire.
- 一号相位炮，射击 - 一号相位炮，射击
- Phaser one, fire. - Phaser one, fire.
- 二号相位炮，射击 - 二号相位炮，射击
- Phaser two, fire. - Phaser two, fire.
将所有能量转移到武器上去
Divert all power to weapons.
相位炮超负荷，控制电路烧毁
Phaser overload. Control-circuit burnout.
- 长官，修复得花些时间 - 舰长，他们是要投降吗？
- It'll take time to correct, sir. - Captain, are they surrendering?
全速后退，启动紧急曲速
Full astern! Emergency warp speed!
开启紧急曲速了吗？
- Do we have emergency warp?
长官，已全速开启，他们的速度仍快过我们
Full power, sir. It's still overtaking us.
长官，只要再用相位炮打一炮
If we can get one phaser working, sir
我们就胜利了
one shot will detonate it.
导航
Navigation?
长官，预计对方将在2分钟后追上我们
Estimate it will overtake us in two minutes, sir.
- 史波克，相位炮 - 舰长，用不了
- Phasers, Mr. Spock? - Impossible, captain.
把这个放入太空记录器里然后马上弹射出去
Feed this to the space recorder and jettison immediately.
舰长，我是应该继续做记录还是…？
Captain, should I continue log entry or--?
文书…
Yeoman...
- 是的，继续做记录 - 遵命，长官
- Affirmative, continue log entries. - Yes, sir.
10秒后两舰相撞
Ten seconds to impact.
舰长，目标正在消散，长官
Captain, it's dissipating, sir.
对方的攻击一定有射程限制
It must have a range limit.
5、4、3
Five, four, three,
2、1，撞击
two, one, impact.
射程受限
Limited range.
舰长，相位炮能用了
Phasers operational, captain.
敌方方位111，标记14
Intruder bearing 111, mark 14.
回到最初的航线上去了
Back to his old course.
舰长，对方可能以为我们已经舰毁人亡了
He may think we're destroyed, captain.
这种假设我可不会做
I wouldn't make that assumption.
我想对方舰长也不会做
I don't think their captain will either.
敌方平稳行驶，航线111，标记14
Intruder holding steady. Course 111, mark 14.
苏鲁，和以前一样
Same as before, Mr. Sulu.
跟着他
Stay with him.
中校，他们又跟上来了
Commander, the reflection returns.
- 开启隐匿装置 - 中校，快没燃料了
- Activate our cloak. - Commander, our fuel runs low.
快
Quickly!
那艘地球舰船吗？
The Earth vessel?
- 这不可能 - 我们动对方也动
- Impossible. - It moves as we move.
对方指挥官不会重蹈覆辙
Its commander is not one to repeat a mistake.
舰长，一分钟后抵达中立区
We enter the Neutral Zone in one minute, captain.
舰长，我们违反条约了吗？
Do we violate the treaty, captain?
医生，对方违约在前
They did, doctor.
一旦进入中立区，他们可以说是我们违约在先，给我们下套
Once inside, they can claim we did. A setup.
他们想打仗，而我们给了他们开战的理由
They want war, we furnish the provocation.
舰长，我们还没到中立区
We're still on our side, captain.
那就在进入中立区之前
Let's get them while we are.
拿下他们
Before we enter the Neutral Zone.
苏鲁，全速前进，曲速最大化
Full ahead, Mr. Sulu, maximum warp.
长官，已全速前进，最大曲速已开启
Ahead, sir, maximum.
- 相位炮待命 - 长官，从此处发射吗？
- Phasers, stand by. - Sir, at this distance?
斯泰尔斯，我们知道了对方的软肋
We know their Achilles heel, Mr. Stiles.
他们的武器占用了所有的能量
Their weapon takes all their energy.
隐形无法使用武器
They must become visible in order to launch it.
射程这么远还能打中算是走狗屎运了
A phaser hit at this distance would be the wildest stroke of luck.
斯泰尔斯，我知道
I'm aware of that, Mr. Stiles.
相位炮准备好了吗？
Are phasers ready?
长官，相位炮准备完毕
Phasers show ready, sir.
中校
Commander!
展开防御
Evasive action.
又是那艘地球舰船
The Earth ship again.
长官，20秒后抵达中立区
Twenty seconds to Neutral Zone, sir.
乌乎拉上尉…
Lieutenant Uhura...
通知指挥部
...inform Command Base.
依我之见，此时别无选择
In my opinion, no option.
我们将驶入中立区
On my responsibility...
一切责任由我来承担
...we are proceeding into the Neutral Zone.
苏鲁，匀速前进，继续射击
Steady as we go, Mr. Sulu. Continue firing.
中校，他们赶上来了
Commander, they stay within range!
- 我来照顾百夫长 - 不用
- I will tend to the Centurion. - No need.
百夫长已死
Centurion is dead.
中校，我们为什么不反击？
Why don't we fire, commander?
不…
No...
敌方舰长是个精明的人
No, he's shrewd, this starship commander.
他想逼我们浪费能量
He tries to make us waste energy.
他料到我们只够…
He has estimated we have only enough...
是时候了
It is time.
- 将所有碎片送入垃圾管中 - 遵命，中校
- All debris into disposal tubes. - Yes, commander.
百夫长的遗体也一并送进去吧
The body of the Centurion too.
原谅我，我的老朋友…
Forgive me, my old friend...
但现在我必须竭尽所能返回家园
...but I must use all my experience now to get home.
动作传感器信号中断
Motion-sensor signal stopped.
- 停火 - 长官，前方有碎片
- Cease-fire. - Debris scattering ahead, sir.
- 我们打中了 - 史波克
- We've hit them. - Mr. Spock?
飞船残骸，金属模具，导管，塑料制品
Vessel wreckage. Metal moulds, conduit, Plastiform...
长官，还有一具尸体，但是…
...and a body, captain. However...
- 但是什么？ - 长官，质量不够
- However? - Insufficient mass, sir.
- 什么？ - 只是些碎片
- What? - Simple debris.
不是舰船，我们中计了
Not a vessel, a trick.
- 传感器检测结果 - 长官，什么也没检测到
- Go to sensor probes. - Nothing, sir.
无任何运动迹象
No motion out there at all.
长官，我们跟丢了
We've lost them, captain.
舰长日志，星历1709.6
Captain's log, stardate 1709.6.
我们身处中立区
We are at the Neutral Zone.
现已和敌方失去了联系
Have lost contact with the intruder.
运动传感器表明无移动迹象
No reaction on our motion sensors,
但我相信罗慕兰人关闭了舰船所有的引擎和系统
but believe the Romulan vessel to be somewhere close by
潜伏在附近某处
with all engines and systems shut down.
进取号也静静地等待着
The Enterprise is also playing the silent waiting game
希望能再次获得对方的消息
in hope of regaining contact.
舰长
Captain.
转换线圈又失效了，必须进一步的修补
I must make further repairs on the transfer coil. It’s giving out again.
好，史波克，别出声
All right, Mr. Spock. Work quietly.
中校，转了整整20圈了，仍未发现对方
Now 20 full cycles, commander. Still no sign.
我认为对方中招了
I say he's been fooled.
他肯定已经离开了
He must've gone on.
他还在某个地方，我感觉得到
He is there. Somewhere. I feel it.
舰长日志，内容补充
Captain's log, supplemental.
进取号现已静止9小时47分
Now motionless for nine hours, 47 minutes.
长官，我从厨房给你拿些食物吧
Can I get you something from the galley, sir?
起码喝杯咖啡吧
Coffee, at least?
谢谢你，文书
Thank you, yeoman.
把咖啡送去舰桥，我一会儿就到
Bring it to the bridge. I'll be there in a moment.
知道了，长官
Yes, sir.
我希望我正在大海某处长途旅行
I wish I were on a long sea voyage somewhere.
没有太多的甲板网球，没有疯狂的跳舞
Not too much deck tennis, no frantic dancing
没有责任
and no responsibility.
为什么是我？
Why me?
环顾舰桥…
I look around that bridge...
船员正等着我作出下一步行动的指示
...and I see the men waiting for me to make the next move.
老骨头…
And, Bones...
如果我错了怎么办？
...what if I'm wrong?
- 舰长 - 我并不是真的想要个答案
- Captain-- - I don't really expect an answer.
但我有了一个
But I've got one.
有些事我极少对…
Something I seldom say to a...
对客人提起，吉姆
...customer, Jim.
在银河系里
In this galaxy,
理论上可能存在3百万颗地球这样的行星
there's a mathematical probability of 3 million Earth-type planets.
而在整个宇宙里
And in all of the universe,
则有3万亿个银河系这样的星系
3 million million galaxies like this.
而在这些星系里
And in all of that...
也许数量更甚于此…
...and perhaps more...
我们每个人都是独一无二的
...only one of each of us.
别毁了那个叫寇克的人
Don't destroy the one named Kirk.
- 什么？ - 没事儿
- What? - It's all right.
没事儿
It's all right.
中校，发现信号
A signal, commander.
找到他们了
We have him.
朝对方前进
Move toward him.
启动引擎
Power on.
掉头行驶，否则对方会从我们眼前溜走
Reverse course. He'll try to slip under us.
- 长官，侧面推力已开启 - 长官，正在转向
- Lateral power, sir. - Coming around, sir.
相位炮，发射
Phasers, fire.
中校，怎么会这样？会这样？
How, commander? How?
那个人是个巫师，他猜透了我的想法
He's a sorcerer, that one. He reads the thoughts in my brain.
我们的燃料用光了，而对方却遥不可及
Our fuel supply all but gone, and he stays out of reach.
我们被打败了
We are beaten!
这会是真的吗？
Can it be true?
执行官最引以为豪的头号旗舰被打败了
The Praetor's finest and proudest flagship, beaten!
也许我们还能挽救你们执行官的尊严
Perhaps we can yet save your Praetor's pride for him.
往导管里放入更多的碎片
More debris into the tubes!
德西乌斯，船上有老式的核子弹头吗？
Decius, do we have some of the old-style nuclear warheads aboard?
有，中校，但只用于自毁
Yes, commander, but only for self-destruction.
往放碎片的导管里放一个
Place one in with the debris. Proximity fuse.
遵命，中校，立即执行
Yes, commander. At once.
长官，残骸越来越多，都落在航线上了
More wreckage, sir, scattering across our path.
- 停火 - 探测仪探测到碎片
- Cease-fire. - Debris on our scanners.
- 快点儿分析 - 长官，和之前的碎片一个类型
- Analysis, quickly. - Same type as before, sir.
除了一个金属外壳的物体
Except one metal-cased object.
舵手，满舵
Helm, hard over!
- 相位炮，近距离发射 - 相位炮已发射
- Phasers, fire. Point-blank! - Phasers, fire!
荣耀，荣耀啊
Glorious. Glorious!
现在启程回家
Now we go home.
对方在我们控制之下
They are at our mercy.
中校…
Commander...
我得提醒一下你的职责所在
...I remind you of your duty.
- 舰长呼叫医务室 - 我是麦考伊
- Captain to Sickbay. - McCoy here.
- 伤亡人数多少？ - 目前为止21人
- Casualties? - Twenty-two so far.
主要是辐射烧伤，大多来自舰船外围区域
Mainly radiation burns, mostly from the ship's outer areas.
舰长，情况本会更糟糕
Could've been much, much worse, captain.
医生，谢谢你
Thank you, doctor.
史波克，提交报告
Report, Mr. Spock.
长官，是某种核设备
Nuclear device of some kind, sir.
我们的相位炮
Our phasers detonated it
- 在不到100米处引爆了它 - 舰船损毁情况
- less than 100 metres away. - Ship damage?
主要是引擎过载和线路烧毁
Mainly overloads and circuit burnouts.
- 武器呢 - 只剩下前方相位炮室了
- Weapons status. - Only the Forward Phaser Room.
- 史考特，能正常使用吗？ - 能，长官
- Fully operable, Scotty? - Yes, sir.
但只有汤姆林森专员一人在操作
But Specialist Tomlinson is manning it alone.
没有后备人员
No standby crew available.
长官，我的第一个岗位是在武器控制岗
Sir, my first assignment was in Weapons Control.
去吧，乌乎拉上尉，接管导航
Go. Lieutenant Uhura, take over navigation.
遵命，舰长
Yes, captain.
舰长，引擎现已恢复供能
We have engine power now, captain,
如果你想离开此处去修葺舰船
if you'd like to move off and make repairs.
不，不
No, no.
也许我们能将对方拉回我们的地盘
Maybe we can pull them back to our side of the Neutral Zone.
原地不动
Hold our position.
装死
Play dead.
仍无移动的迹象
Still no sign of movement.
我们元气大伤，储备燃料也已用尽
We have damaged ourselves. Our fuel reserve is gone.
粉碎执行官的敌人是我们的职责所在
And it is our duty to crush the Praetor's enemies.
我不相信敌方舰长
I do not trust their captain.
我们在中立区，他们不会进来
We are in the Neutral Zone. They will not enter.
中校，如果你不肯，那就让我光荣的去死吧
If you refuse, permit me the glory of the kill, commander.
我们会进攻…
We will attack.
但得听我指挥
But on my order.
斯泰尔斯，提交损毁报告
Damage reports, Mr. Stiles.
- 无损毁 - 你需要帮助吗？
- Negative. - Will you require any assistance here?
瓦肯人，这次我们地球人自己会处理，不需要你的帮助
This time, we'll handle things without your help, Vulcan.
相位炮密封冷却剂 （危险）
汤姆林森…
Tomlinson...
长官，敌方舰船现形了
Enemy vessel becoming visible, sir.
前方相位炮，待命
Forward phasers, stand by.
发射
Fire.
Fire!
斯泰尔斯，听见命令了吗？发射
Stiles, can you hear me? Fire!
发射！斯泰尔斯，听见了吗？给我发射
Fire! Stiles, can you hear me? Fire!
发射
Fire!
斯泰尔斯，能听见我说话吗？发射啊
Stiles, can you hear me? Fire!
斯泰尔斯！
Stiles!
他们向我们开炮了
They're firing at us!
苏鲁，准备朝罗慕兰飞船逼近
Mr. Sulu, prepare to move in on the Romulan vessel.
乌乎拉，开启舰船间通信系统
Ship-to-ship, Uhura.
- 把信号转到屏幕上去 - 长官，呼叫频率打开
- Put this on the screen. - Hailing frequencies open, sir.
舰长…
Captain...
做好准备，将生还者传送到进取号上来
...standing by to beam your survivors aboard our ship.
做好弃舰准备
Prepare to abandon your vessel.
不
No.
不，这不是我们的风格
No, it is not our way.
我们以这种方式碰面，对此我深表遗憾
I regret that we meet in this way.
你我本是同类
You and I are of a kind.
却生活在不同的国度里
In a different reality,
我本该称呼你一声“朋友”
I could've called you "friend."
服从至死有何意义？
What purpose will it serve to die?
舰长，我们肩负着责任
We are creatures of duty, captain.
责任是我生存的意义
I have lived my life by it.
我还有最后一个职责得执行
Just one more duty to perform.
史波克，你还好吧
You all right, Mr. Spock?
没事儿，我很好，谢谢你，舰长
Yes, very well. Thank you, captain.
- 斯泰尔斯，你呢？ - 活得好好的，长官
- And you, Mr. Stiles? - I'm alive, sir.
本来我必死无疑了
But I wouldn't be.
史波克拖着我离开了相位炮室
Mr. Spock, he pulled me out of the Phaser Room.
冒着生命危险救了我一命，在我…
Saved my life. He risked his life, and after I--
我救了一名训练有素的导航员
I saved a trained navigator
这样他就能回去当差了
so that he could return to duty.
这种事情我可没注入什么感情因素
I am capable of no other feelings in such matters.
- 老骨头，我们失去了多少人？ - 只有一个
- How many men did we lose, Bones? - Only one.
汤姆林森，今早本来要结婚的那个人
Tomlinson, the boy who was going to get married this morning.
他的未婚妻现在在小礼堂
His fiancée is at the chapel now.
长官，我们终于收到基地的回复了
We finally received an answer from Command Base, sir.
他们说支持你的一切决定
They say they'll support whatever decision you have to make.
这事儿说不清道不明
It never makes any sense.
你我都必须明白事出皆有因
We both have to know that there was a reason.
我没事
I'm all right.
本集结束
谢谢观赏